Finding Aid for Wright family papers, 1825-1938
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Wright family papers
1825-1938
Wright family.
86440 Aa 2; UAx
Philo E. and Fannie E. Pettibone Wright family of Detroit, Michigan. Personal papers of Fannie Wright with her husband Philo, her brother Sherman Pettibone, her daughters Virginia, Maude, and Evelyn, her son Philo S., and other members of the family, concerning family affairs and the genealogy of the Wright and Pettibone families.
3 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was acquired in 1958. Donor no. 1771
No further additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
The Wright-Pettibone-Collier families were residents of Ohio and Detroit, Michigan. Philo Wright was a Great Lakes ship captain.
The collection has been arranged by name of family member. Included is personal correspondence of Fannie Wright with her husband Philo E., her brother Sherman Pettibone, daughters Virginia, Maude, and Evelyn, son Philo S., and other members of the family, concerning family affairs and the genealogy of the Wright and Pettibone families. There are also fifty-seven volumes of Fannie E. Wright's diaries, 1863-1925, recording family news, social events, and home activities in Detroit, Michigan. Also of interest are account books of the Sherman Pettibone farm of Tallmadge, Ohio, and account books of Philo S. Wright, 1893-1913. Photographs in the collection consist of individual and group portraits of family members; photographs of family homes; and photographs of boating on the Detroit River.
Subjects:
Agriculture.; Collier, Victory P.; Collier family.; Detroit (Mich.); Great Lakes (North America); Michigan--Social life and customs--1861-1870.; Michigan--Social life and customs--1871-1880.; Michigan--Social life and customs--1881-1890.; Michigan--Social life and customs--1891-1900.; Michigan--Social life and customs--1901-1910.; Michigan--Social life and customs--1911-1920.; Michigan--Social life and customs--1921-1930.; Ohio.; Pettibone family.; Ships--Great Lakes (North America); Stanley, David Sloane, 1828-1902.; Tallmadge (Ohio); Women--Michigan--Detroit.; Wright family.; Michigan--Social life and customs--19th century.; Michigan--Social life and customs--20th century.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Boats.; Clothing and dress--1901-1910.; Detroit River (Mich. and Ont.); Dwellings.; Interiors.; Men--Clothing and dress--1921-1930.; Offices.; Women.; Wright family.
Contributors:
Collier, William W.; Pettibone, Samuel.; Wright, Fannie E. Pettibone, 1836-1925.; Wright, Philo Elizar, 1828-1876.; Wright, Philo Sherman, 1862-
Genre Terms:
Account books.; Diaries.; Photographs.; Tintypes.
- Dr. Philo Wright (Ohio Doctor)
  - Correspondence
    - With family members, 1861-1864 (Box 1)
    - With family members, 1865-1871 (Box 1)
- Philo E. Wright (Great Lakes Captain, son of Dr. Philo Wright)
  - Correspondence
    - With friends and relatives, 1850s (Box 1)
    - Undated, with wife and family (Box 1)
    - With wife and family, 1860s-1870s (Box 1)
    - With wife and family, 1861-1869 (Box 1)
    - With wife and family, 1870-1876 (Box 1)
- Fannie E. Wright (Mrs. Philo E. Wright, nee' Frances Pettibone)
  - Correspondence
    - Undated (Box 1)
    - 1867-1877 (Box 1)
    - 1878-1884 (Box 1)
    - 1885-1890 (Box 1)
    - 1892-1898 (Box 1)
    - 1905-1915 (Box 1)
    - 1917-1929 (Box 1)
    - With son Philo S. Wright, 1882-1887 (Box 1)
    - With son Philo S. Wright, 1892-1893 (Box 1)
    - With brother Sherman Pettibone, 1872-1907 (Box 1)
    - With brother Sherman Pettibone, 1909-1914 (Box 1)
    - With brother Sherman Pettibone, 1915-1918 (Box 1)
  - Diaries, 1863-1891 (Box 1)
  - Diaries, 1892-1911 (Box 2)
  - Diaries, 1912-1925 (Box 2)
- Virginia Wright Collier (daughter of Philo E. and Fannie Wright)
  - Correspondence
    - 1877-1885 (Box 3)
    - Letters and materials relating to Mexico and the Stanley Expedition, 1885 (Box 3)
    - 1886-1899 (Box 3)
    - 1904-1934 (Box 3)
  - Poems, circa 1880-1925 (Box 3)
- William Wallace Collier (husband of Virginia Wright Collier)
  - Papers, relating to the estate of Victory P. Collier, Pres. of the National Bank of Battle Creek, and to the estate of W.W. Collier.
    - Undated, 1890s; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - 1900-1910, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - 1920s (Box 3)
    - 1930s (Box 3)
- Sherman Pettibone (brother of Fannie E. Wright)
  - Correspondence
    - circa 1825-1842 (Box 3)
    - 1882-1910 (Box 3)
    - 1911-1918 (Box 3)
  - Essays, undated (Box 3)
  - Account books, of Sherman Pettibone Farm, Tallmadge, Ohio, 1903-1911 (Box 3)
- Genealogical Information
  - Wright family (Box 3)
  - Pettibone family, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Families associated with the Wright family, including the Birdsey and Seeley families (Box 3)
- Other materials
  - Correspondence (miscellaneous) (Box 3)
  - Miscellanea (Box 3)
  - Photographs
    (see also tintypes stored with UAx photographs)
    - Individuals, female (Box 3)
    - Individuals, male (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 3)